

□ (+45) 60 90 60 12 | 🗷 erik@i-solution.de | 💿 0000-0002-4984-7646 | 🌴 www.erikkusch.com | 🖫 ErikKusch | 💆 KuschErik | 🛅 Kusch Erik

Research Profile

I am a macroecologist specialised in remote sensing applications and spatio-temporal analyses. I use quantitative tools to research ecosystem resilience, vegetation dynamics, and patterns of landscape-scale biodiversity to understand past, present, and future trajectories of natural ecosystems. Current work includes identification of species-interaction networks, software development for climate data retrieval and aggregation, and propagation of uncertainty of climatic data into biological analyses.

Education

PhD in Biology; Specialisation on Ecoinformatics and Biodiversity

01/2020 - PRESENT

AARHUS UNIVERSITY (AU) & OXFORD UNIVERSITY (OX)

Primary Advisor: Alejandro Ordonez (AU)

External Supervision: Roberto Salguero-Gómez (OX)

Contents: Climate data practices in biological research

Species interaction inference and network modelling Species extinction and extinction cascade simulations

M.Sc. in Biology; Specialisation on Biodiversity, Ecology and Evolution

08/2017 - 08/2019

University of Bergen (UiB) & Nansen Environmental and Remote Sensing Center (Nansen)

Primary Advisor: Alistair Seddon (UiB) External Supervision: Richard Davy (Nansen)

Thesis: Inferring Vegetation Memory from Remote Sensing Data and identifying Causal Links to Plant Function

B.Sc. in Biology 10/2013 - 07/2017

TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY DRESDEN (TUD) & UNIVERSITY OF BERGEN (UIB)

Primary Advisor: Alistair Seddon (UiB) Secondary Supervision: Klaus Reinhardt (TUD)

Thesis: Remote Sensing And Predicting Shifts In Biome Distribution And Resilience Using NDVI Data

Specialised Training

7th Edition Species Distribution Modelling Course

Évora, Portugal

University of Évora, Science Retreats

26/04/2021 - 02/05/2021

An Introduction to Bayesian Statistics

Glasgow, Scotland 06/04/2021 - 16/04/2021

University of Glasgow

Hamburg, Germany

Modelling Challenges for Mountain Ecosystems

23/02/2020 - 28/02/2020

University of Hamburg

Wayauecha Biological Station, Peru

Plant Functional Traits Course 3

08/03/2018 - 24/03/2018

University of Bergen (UiB), University of Arizona (UoA) **Bayesian Modelling Summer School**

Lygra, Norway

Norwegian University of Life Sciences (NMBU)

25/10/2017 - 29/10/2017

Experience

Research Fellow

Research Station Co-Manager

Scoraig, Scotland

SPATIAL AND POPULATION ECOLOGY, UNIVERSITY OF GLASGOW

06/2019 - PRESENT

ECOLOGICAL AND ENVIRONMENTAL CHANGE RESEARCH GROUP, UNIVERSITY OF BERGEN

Bergen, Norway

Notice of Book Book and Continuous and Education College

09/2019 - 12/2019 Saxony, Germany

National Park Ranger & Environmental Education Guide
National Park Saxon-Bohemian Swiss

04/2016 - 06/2016

Research and Teaching Assistant

BEHAVIOURAL ECOLOGY RESEARCH GROUP, UNIVERSITY OF LEIPZIG

08/2017 - 08/2019; 03/2017 - 04/2017

PRIMATE RESEARCH CENTRE, UNIVERSITY OF KYOTO

07/2018

GERMAN CENTRE FOR MARINE BIODIVERSITY RESEARCH, SENCKENBERG GROUP

05/2017 - 07/2017

Teaching & Supervision Activity

| Author & Lecturer: AU Bayes Study Group | 🔇 Personal Course Web Page |
|--|-----------------------------------|
| Seminar Series | ♦ Official Course Web Page |
| Author & Lecturer: Excursions into Biostatistics | ♀ Course Web Page |
| Seminar Series | 🖫 GitHub Repository |
| Author & Lecturer: An Introduction to Biostatistics Using R | ♀ Course Web Page |
| TALK SERIES | 🖫 GitHub Repository |
| Author | ♀ Course Web Page |
| BIOLOGICAL RESEARCH IN THEORY AND PRAXIS (BFTP) | Aarhus University |
| Teaching Assistant | Aarhus University |
| Applied Statistics | 22/03/2021 - 14/05/2021 |
| STATISTICAL AND GEOSPATIAL MODELLING | 03/09/2020 - 18/12/2020 |
| GEOSPATIAL INFORMATION SYSTEMS | 27/10/2020 - 18/12/2020 |
| Instructor & Advisor | |
| ECOINFORMATICS & BIODIVERSITY MASTERS SEMINARS (EBMS), AARHUS UNIVERSITY | 03/02/2021 - 05/05/2021 |

Extracurricular Activity

Group Member

| STATISTICS JOURNAL CLUB, UNIVERSITY OF GLASGOW | 10/03/2021 - PRESENT |
|--|----------------------|
| Spatial Shared-Interest Group, University of Glasgow | 10/03/2021 - PRESENT |
| Bayes Study Group, University of Bergen | 09/2018 - 12/2019 |
| EECRG Reading Group, University of Bergen | 10/2017 - 12/2019 |
| | |

08/2017 - 07/2018

Dresden, Germany

Elected Member: Students Council of Biology Studies at the TUD

CENTRE OF EXCELLENCE IN BIODIVERSITY EDUCATION (BIOCEED), UNIVERSITY OF BERGEN

TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY OF DRESDEN 10/2013 - 10/2015

Honours & Grants & Awards _____

SCHOLARSHIPS & GRANTS

| Scholarship for Academically Excellent Students , Frands Christian Frantsen's Scholarship | Aarhus, Denmark |
|--|---|
| Funding for Particularly Talented Students, Lina Asbjørnsens Stipendiefond | Bergen, Norway |
| Fast-Track-Initiative Funding, FTI, Bjerknessenteret | Bergen, Norway |
| Project Grant, L. Meltzers Høyskolefond | Bergen, Norway |
| Scholarship , German Academic Scholarship Foundation (Studienstiftung des deutschen Volkes) | Bonn, Germany |
| | Funding for Particularly Talented Students, Lina Asbjørnsens Stipendiefond Fast-Track-Initiative Funding, FTI, Bjerknessenteret Project Grant, L. Meltzers Høyskolefond |

AWARDS

| 10/2019 | Best Poster: Student and Early Career Researcher , International Society for Ecological Modelling | Salzburg, Austria |
|---------|--|-------------------|
| 10/2019 | Modeller's Choice Poster Award, International Society for Ecological Modelling | Salzburg, Austria |

| 25/03/2021 Aarhus, Denmark 12/11/2020 18/06/2020 25/06/2020 15/10/2019 06/09/2019 Bergen, Norway 15/03/2019 |
|--|
| 12/11/2020 18/06/2020 25/06/2020 15/10/2019 04/10/2019 06/09/2019 Bergen, Norway 15/03/2019 |
| 18/06/2020 25/06/2020 15/10/2019 04/10/2019 06/09/2019 Bergen, Norway |
| 25/06/2020 15/10/2019 04/10/2019 06/09/2019 Bergen, Norway 15/03/2019 |
| 25/06/2020 15/10/2019 04/10/2019 06/09/2019 Bergen, Norway 15/03/2019 |
| 15/10/2019 04/10/2019 06/09/2019 Bergen, Norway 15/03/2019 |
| 04/10/2019 06/09/2019 Bergen, Norway 15/03/2019 |
| 04/10/2019 06/09/2019 Bergen, Norway 15/03/2019 |
| 06/09/2019 Bergen, Norway 15/03/2019 |
| Bergen, Norway 15/03/2019 |
| 15/03/2019 |
| |
| Clara C |
| Glasgow, Scotland |
| 09/01/2019 |
| |
| |
| 25/06/2020 |
| 03/10/2019 |
| 16/09/2019 |
| |
| |

Vegetation memory effects and their association with vegetation resilience in global drylands

LEADING AUTHOR

2020

Rχ Preprint

2021

KrigR - A Tool for Downloading and Statistically Downscaling Climate Reanalysis

Data

LEADING AUTHOR